Everything you've heard is true.
The Blair Witch Project is a horror, mystery film directed by Daniel Myrick.
In October of 1994 three student filmmakers disappeared in the woods near
Burkittsville, Maryland, while shooting a documentary.
A year later their footage was found.
Heather Donahue, played by Heather Donahue.
Joshua Leonard, played by Joshua Leonard.
Michael Williams, played by Michael C. Williams.
Short Fisherman, played by Bob Griffin.
Interviewee (uncredited), played by Jim King.
Waitress, played by Sandra Sánchez.
The Blair Witch Project is a 1999 American found footage psychological folk horror
film written, directed, and edited by Daniel Myrick and Eduardo Sánchez.
One of the most successful independent films of all time, it is a "found footage"
pseudo-documentary in which three students (Heather Donahue, Michael C.
Williams, and Joshua Leonard) hike into the Appalachian Mountains near Burkittsville,
Maryland, to shoot a documentary about a local myth known as the Blair Witch.
Myrick and Sánchez conceived of a fictional legend of the Blair Witch in 1993.
They developed a 35-page screenplay with the dialogue to be improvised.
A casting call advertisement on Backstage magazine was prepared by the
directors; Donahue, Williams, and Leonard were cast.
The film entered production in October 1997, with the
principal photography lasting eight days.
Most of the filming was done on the Greenway Trail along
Seneca Creek in Montgomery County, Maryland.
About 20 hours of footage was shot, which was edited down to 82 minutes.
Shot on an original budget of $35,000–$60,000, the film had a final cost
of $200,000–$750,000 after post-production and marketing.
When The Blair Witch Project premiered at the Sundance Film Festival at midnight on January 23, 1999,
its promotional marketing campaign listed the actors as either "missing" or "deceased".
Due to its successful Sundance run, Artisan Entertainment bought
the film's distribution rights for $1.1 million.
The film had a limited release on July 14 of the same year, before
expanding to a wider release starting on July 30.
While the film received critical acclaim, audience reception was polarized.
The Blair Witch Project was a sleeper hit that
grossed nearly $250 million worldwide.
It is consistently listed as one of the scariest movies of all time, and was ranked the best found
footage movie of all time by editors from both IndieWire and Entertainment Weekly.
Despite the success, the three main actors had reportedly lived in poverty.
In 2000, they sued Artisan Entertainment claiming unfair
compensation, eventually reaching a $300,000 settlement.
The Blair Witch Project launched a media franchise, which includes two sequels (Book
of Shadows and Blair Witch), novels, comic books, and video games.
It revived the found-footage technique and influenced similarly successful horror films
such as Paranormal Activity (2007), REC (2007) and Cloverfield (2008).
The film explores themes of witch, legend, camping, map, supernatural.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.